hello my name is green and i've started
today's episode very quickly because ren
has left me a message saying that he's
left a little present for me from big
logs to do a deal with sahara
and he he forgot to tell me at the dare
game now ren is dead you can see that
because he's monochrome there in the tab
list he died by my hand and now all of a
sudden he wants to make a deal with
sahara well
that's sus that's really sus
and a little bit predictable
red dog so he's left a present at sahara
so we're gonna go check that out and see
what he's done
he's actually physically made a present
a real present
this
looks so suspicious
if you've been playing hermitcraft long
enough or even just minecraft long
enough you know
not to take anything that's in a big
suspicious box
too seriously because this
is quite clearly
very
i don't know i don't know what it does
maybe it explodes maybe it drops me into
lava i don't know let's have a look for
the marketing department only aka green
a donation from big logs incorporated
we've got excess stocks can we have a
meeting to talk business deal
rent dog that is so suspicious ren this
is the worst trap you need you need to
be more subtle
he just goes on to the dead team and
then this happens
there's a very suspicious chest and i
can't tell whether it's rigged or not
hold on that we can we can totally deal
with this so if we actually
head over quickly to this little potion
shop
we take a fire resistance we take a
health potion
and we take and we might as well take
some golden apples as well so we'll take
two healings and a fire resistance pop
in a diamond there we could just totally
play this out because one way or another
we will survive
so if this drops me in lava
the fire resistance potion is gonna take
care of that i've got a healing potion
if things go badly and i've got a totem
of undying if something blows up
so this should be pretty safe
yeah i do it i do it and
and i could just oh i could just fly
wait is there something bad at the
bottom nope there's absolutely nothing
rendog
you gotta up your game
you've got to up your game i was so
ready for this on so many levels
okay so it was a pitfall trap
not a problem and we're out flown out
easy peasy
ah ren ren ren ren ren
big sus box
do not enter
oh man the only danger is if one of the
other architects see oh there's a
present from big logs incorporated no no
no look it says big sus box do not enter
and then i've even just safety that so
it should be fine wait was there even
any logs in here nothing no logs
useless
well we have escaped death once more and
ren said no hard feelings he said no
hard feelings
well it looks like someone's targeting
us already so that means we've got to be
a bit more careful and we've got to
continue making our bunker even more
safe
so let's head on down into the bunker
which still doesn't have a proper
entrance iskall please if you're if
you're watching my dude
we need an entrance to this thing
and let's continue building what we
started hang on go this way go this way
to get an actually secure bunker what
does that mean there's absolutely
nothing here am i blind i genuinely
don't see
is it a joke
oh wait no wait wait there is actually
something here uh key cards for
architects access to secure mumbanger
no let me into my let me in my compound
let me in
let me in not sure why he's got iron
doors wow really okay wait is this a
trick i'm i'm so paranoid of everything
um
how long is this i've been traveling
for like
10 hours
it doesn't end
this tunnel is so long let's see if i
can get a fly going this would be so
much easier if i can fly down yeah there
we go now we're cooking
see how long this tunnel is even when
you're flying
wait
there's an end there's an end
no
no it doesn't end are we near the end
is this a joke
it legit keeps going wait here we are
we're at the end we just got a load of
buffs from a beacon somewhere oh my
goodness
that is a long tunnel
s-r-a-m
compound lava arrow activate bunk
hmm
we gotta find out what all the stuff
does arrow activator
bunker lava
oh
no
okay
so they're all defenses uh
sorry mumbo so this is the mumbo bunk
there okay so he's got a panic room
there's a bedroom in here so mumbo's
gone and made himself an uh
another bunker oh wait i'm guessing that
was the arrow defense oh
nelly
where are we
i feel like i'm in prison
mumbo this isn't a bunker this is a
prison
was this his was this his goal all along
oh my goodness no we're right near his
base
look how far
we traveled underground we walked all
this way
underground
i'm not even sure what to make of this
that tunnel is so long it's much quicker
just to fly above ground well that was a
long journey and we ended up exactly
where we were before so i guess what
we're going to do now is continue the
real bunker not the not the mumbo prison
that he's got going on we're gonna
continue making this thing which should
end up being really really cool all
right let's get into it so the plan is
still building on from what we did last
time i still want this to be an
underground cave like villain style
layer but i also want to leave plenty of
room for all of the defenses that we
want to make so most of the important
stuff will be at the back whereas i'm
going to leave most of the floor open so
i've basically decorated the walls with
the cave sides and you can see i used
some concrete to create some pillars and
then the main attraction is all the way
at the back so this will allow me in the
future to make traps along that big open
space where all of the torch spam is and
this is the end result look at this i
wouldn't exactly call this finished and
we clearly have a few problems to
overcome i had a really
really close call during the recording
of this uh time lapse i'll i'll show a
clip of it now check it out because i
have the replay mod running you can see
there's the creeper up there i have no
idea he's there he jumps down and i
still don't know he's there until he
lands you can see me look up wait is
that a creeper and then i look down and
i go oh no
that's a creeper and then i try and run
away but it's too late and look what it
does it's like
no
thank goodness i lived half a heart
stupid creepers
okay so as you can see this is
nearly done or at least we've got a
shell i've made most of the cave i've
got it like nicely detailed it's kind of
lit up there's obviously a few issues
but this gives us a nice space to work
with and defend and to trap properly and
it definitely looks like uh some sort of
bond villain layer which is is really
cool so now we've got to go over and get
some more resources and plan out what
we're going to do over here oh my looks
like the the clock's still ticking
demise game might still be happening but
whatever is going on here with cherry
seems to still be happening not sure
though i hope the other architect guys
haven't messed with this ren's
present i'm pretty sure this hasn't been
touched yeah it still says big sus box
don't enter but hold on didn't work once
try it again what's this enjoy now who
made the
like seriously guys
if you if if you die in demise
and you want to trap something
making a big obvious button box
definitely isn't the way to go now how
do we tackle this one how do we tackle
this one so i've got my totem of undying
tell you what i can take another potion
of fire resistance not that i think
anything's gonna happen with lava here
let's take a little inspection of this
box they can try and get me but they're
just not gonna i'm gonna be prepared i'm
gonna be ready with my rockets and my
tote of undying some random materials
here so we got buttons galore it just
says enjoy us all the information we've
got okay
right
this is so suspicious why is the button
so far away oh
wait what it just
i mean it wasn't an arrow or anything it
gave me a totem totem of undying so
there's only one of those so one of
these is an issue one of these has got
to give you something bad
oh that okay that was an end of what is
it's just giving gifts
maybe this wait maybe this isn't
something maybe this is a present for
architects wait did someone did someone
do a deal that i'm not aware of and this
is part of it
what was that
that might have been coal
yeah okay that was cole hold on if i can
that's why the buttons are so far away
so i'm forced to stand here
what was that bone meal i think that was
bone meal
yeah bone meal
we're just getting gifts what was that
oh golden apple golden apple
there's an egg
none of these these aren't dangerous and
two more what was that
a book boo
uh so that was
a whole lot of nothing any anything else
no
and
nothing is this one empty
right so let's put that back because i
don't i don't actually need most of this
stuff
so there's loads of eggs in that one
coal i got a coal back well very nice of
you to give me gifts but i
i don't really need them
what was in here oh there's a totem of
undying in here
brilliant
so what was meant to be in this one then
no
wait so why didn't that work why isn't
that dispensing
there's a dragon head cursive binding
that says demise doesn't oh wait
it's because i'm wearing a helmet it's
because i've already got something on my
helmet it can't dispense on me
um i think someone didn't think this
through particularly well well i'll tell
you what i'm definitely going to take
the totem of undying because you know
you can't have too many totems but
everything else i think can probably
stay in there that's funny i'm just
going to leave this here and see if
anyone else falls for it because that
is bad that means you are stuck with
that helmet without any armor on your
head for the rest of the game and
because
uh because
i think they don't have durability you
can't even break it off of you
so that's that's but that's really
devious but um i don't think they
thought that through because i got my
golden helmet on so um thanks for the
gifts i guess
so now i need to quickly meet up with
iskall who apparently has actually
installed a front door to our bunker
which is a pretty big deal and he said
he said in big capital letters green
don't go in the bunker it's dangerous so
i better i better meet up with him and
see see what he's saying hello mr alive
friend hello mr eli friend hold on yep
where's your t-shirt is no t-shirt no
service in in sahara
i know i i do feel like i have to
apologize in the middle of winter why
are you it's nearly christmas catch
you know what though i i do have to
actually put some clothes on i'll be
right back there we go that's better i
what is that take off your other armor
it's uh the heck is that why are you you
farmer now are you farmer iskal i'm not
farmer look at my look at my hair
i'm dorothy man i look i look fabulous
though
i look fabulous anyway enough about the
clothes you asked me to build a secret
entrance to the architect bunker yes
have you done it er
i i've just completed it and i have for
you
this thing
which a door
it it's not a it's a why is everyone
using doors for car keys now sorry i'm
gonna have to interrupt this segment of
the video because it was at this moment
that i realized iskal wasn't wearing a
minecraft helmet
and while we were having this exact
conversation all i was thinking about in
my mind is how do i get iskal to press
the button for the dragon head so what
you're about to see is me trying to
gently lead him into doing it
let's see if it works oh dude have you
seen this have you seen this someone
left us a load of presents have you have
you done this
no
i did this look it gave me i got two
totems of undying from this because it
had a present it has presence in it so i
i went and just clicked this stuff and
it like dispenses presents i don't know
who did this by the way but i did i
think someone did a deal with uh
architects or something i don't know
look it's just there's just ultimate
gifts in here huh
okay
it does look like a trap though not
gonna lie no no no i thought so too i
thought too i thought it looked really
like honestly look at them ren made this
box over here and i renamed it giant sus
box and then two days later another
giant sus box appears i think they're
trying to lull us into a false sense of
security or something like this just
does nothing i was super super skeptical
there's just like loads of dispensers
underneath
i've got a piece of coal and i've got
what's the matter i'm sorry
what have you done
what's happened
i'm confused i'm very confused okay i'm
sorry iska i'm sorry someone left this
trap here and it didn't work on me but i
saw you weren't wearing a helmet so
i did it
you gotta be kidding me
i tell you what you look you look much
better as dorothy now
wait wait wait do a little do just walk
just walk slowly forwards for me
oh no
dude this has cursed a binding on it i
can't take it off
you're stuck with it
oh yeah are you serious i have to i have
to die okay so right i don't know i
don't know who made this i don't know
who made this but it's like 50 their
fault 50 percent my fault
oh
my goodness did you know about the hair
i think we were allowed here
i didn't kill you i just put a dragon
head on your head
this has curves of binding i can't get
it off it's a it's a mob head you look
at me
you look amazing
thank you thank you it also looks like
you look so stupid i don't think
it looks so massive and the fact that
your mouth goes open and closed when you
walk like keep walking forward oh yeah
hi i'm ibushka i'm from sweden how are
you today
oh man i i don't think i'm going to be
able to look at you with a straight face
are we even going to go see them i'm
going to absolutely are you mad at me
no no no that was quite that was quite
funny that was quite funny but this is
going to be
interesting
at least you can scare people now i
guess
i could have done that with that right
so the entrance is here right like
no no no no no no no no no more digging
no more digging no more digging so
here's what i've done here's wait is
this it this is this is the secret
entrance try it
ah completely hidden you didn't see that
coming but the button's not hidden is it
i if i wait hold on hold on i'm going to
be i'm going to be one of the dead team
oh look at me i'm rendog blah blah well
i wonder where their secret entrance is
hmm what might this be oh boy
yeah
no no this is this this is this is true
observation
however
it's kind of it's kind of purposely
stupid your head takes up the old head
takes up the entire
the entire corridor
yeah
oh anyway that's kind of the idea i'm
glad that you saw it that way so ren
will come and go hello i'm rendog i'm
from sweden i go down here and and he
thinks then we go down here no no no no
no no no no no no no no
okay breathe so don't go down there
don't go down there no don't go down
there here's the beauty what if i throw
something down here
yeah yeah you can
i can't see because your giant head's in
the way sorry let's draw another one
if anyone discovers the button presses
the button they come down
i can't take it
like this
if
if anyone
no wait turn around look in the corner
and talk to me no no dude seriously look
in the corner there we go okay now
explain it
if anyone comes into the bunker and
presses the button
and then think that they have made their
way into the demise bunker they would be
faced with this
turn around
they will think that they
is so stupid they will think that they
have made their way into the unbreakable
architect bunker
okay okay but in reality
if they try and jump down you know it
looks safe there's water down there it
looks like you're gonna be caught by the
water no problems whatsoever but if they
do jump down without doing a special
things first as you were testing yeah
they fall down opens up they fall 50
block down and and die unless they have
protection for together with feather
falling for yeah
if they do they land on a machine that
will flood the whole basement down there
with lava and then they will die
so where do i put the key card even if
they have a total more fun dying does
this this is disable it then if you
throw it here almost there
yeah for six seconds hold on no now you
feel it
wait
oh
i love how you trusted me by the way i
love how you first checked
to see the the
i heard it go off and i was like oh yeah
i'll be fine now i thought i'd just go
just go
here's the cool thing though if we go
back up
and someone tries this is probably gonna
kill no one except me no no well well
come back up can i just forge
yeah and i can go down no no no no no no
no no do not jump down no that's the
fake that's the fake thing listen close
to the note block listen to this this is
a fake item
listen
right now listen to the real item
okay they're eat their note blocks are
in different places as well yes there's
a slight difference
all right well perfect okay okay do you
like it yeah that's amazing that's
hopefully that will actually protect us
from most intruders
yes that's what i was thinking
all right well that's good because now
we've got the we got the panic button as
well and i have made some progress down
here i don't know if you've seen this
i've made some progress on this now it's
obviously not finished but
this is looking amazing
oh my goodness to build lots of cool
things
and we are making a pact right now i
mean you've put a giant dragon head on
my face
but we're making a pact that as long as
both of us are alive
architects for the win yeah
architecture is an architect win if i
win i will split the diamonds with you
oh okay same all right
deal deal
do we have to discuss what happens if
mumbo wins
i don't believe it
[Laughter]
so yeah we need we need to build this up
and start defending it more and more
and that's it
so now that we've got our bunker
established
iskall's got got the head on him now
um i actually noticed this is from a
really long time ago tango ordered a
bunch of white concrete and i sold him a
whole shulker box so how many diamonds
is this 54 diamonds
pretty cool so just collect that and i
guess that goes on our on our diamond
pile six diamond blocks on not too bad
one two
three there we go
just add them onto the pile
and out we go well i think that's
definitely enough of our bunker i've
definitely had enough of that for now so
i think what i'm gonna do is actually
want to head over to the mini game
district because
i honestly haven't actually played that
many games and that's a real shame so i
wanted to check out a few
now obviously we can't play any games
that are going to kill us so that
actually excludes most of my games
it also excludes ravager run which cub
has told us actually has a single player
mode now there's no way i'm gonna do
this i'm not gonna risk it and then
speedy pines is kind of a multiplayer
game stress messaged me that she had a
mini game somewhere but i'm not sure
where it is
let's try out the pumpkin i think that's
dresses minigame and she messaged me
saying that it was ready to to go and
she said that it definitely wouldn't
kill you so let's see what happens on
this one shall we okay so let's try to
figure out what's going on scoreboard
only one run per hermit note down the
remaining pumpkin tokens on your sign
all right well i'm gonna have to do some
reading this is a time challenge your
goal is to complete the three challenges
to get through the jack-o'-lantern maze
to start the game take three stacks of
pumpkin from the chest behind put all
three stacks into the chest on the left
once you do that the time begins and the
door okay so it looks like it's a time
trial so if i take three stacks of
pumpkins
game starts immediately when you put
your tokens in here okay right
so let's maximize this one two three go
in we go i probably should have made
some space for this
so what do i do guess the halloween song
get all three songs correct to open the
iron door
all right okay uh
song three
[Music]
dun dun dun dun dun dun that's
ghostbusters
[Music]
scooby-doo that's scooby-doo
that's the adams family yeah
i do all of those all right we got uh
we've got a witch in here
the witch
take her take a rod push her wart push
her wart push her what
collect all of her belongings
oh
uh what what do i need a hat oh a hat a
hat oh that's got to be that it's going
to be that's got to be that right no not
that one i can't actually get them what
would be her nose the lapis lazuli might
be her nose okay so if the lapis lazuli
is her nose what would be the eyes
oh wait i have to look at i have to look
at purple eyes purple eye so i need
purple wool
there we go let's get the purple wall
there we go come on why isn't that
covered there we go
that's got to be the hat right uh hat
and the nose
the nose what's the nose the nose is
made out of
something no it's not the bar is it
oh maybe it's the lever
i've got a lever
yes yes okay oh man that took too long
that took way too long open the dark oak
door find your way through
oh man
ah this is this is
find your way through all right so the
door's over there
this might be fastest if i just
plow if i just walk straight through
like this if i just go through here
like that yeah
here we go
and then i get to the end oh man i think
i wasted so much time
i definitely wasted time collect your
pumpkins
from where from where from here whoo
okay so what did we get we got 149
pumpkins
does that mean we're winning at the
moment 136.
no one else is 88
134 yes i think we're in the lead
although there's still quite a lot of
people that need to play this game
oh brilliant okay so i'll just pop these
back
okay i've reset i've reset it for the
next person
and we are done so i guess i only win
something if i get the high score but we
are totally in the running right now we
did well on the music not so good on the
witch because i couldn't figure out what
was meant to be what i just basically
put all of them in the nose
um and then we did pretty well with the
maze we just kind of brute forced it so
that was pretty good i think that is all
from me today so i will see you in the
next episode where we're going to get up
to some more demise shenanigans like for
realsies big demise shenanigans exisumer
void has actually joined the dead team
and that's a pretty big deal because
there are now three members of the dead
team and so it's suddenly become from a
little bit of a risk
to quite a lot of a risk so thank you
very much for watching i will see you in
the next one good bye